soccerbase.com 2017-12-01

# Privacy policy – Racing Post

The Site is owned and operated by Centurycomm Limited trading as Racing Post ("us", "our", "we"). We are committed to protecting the privacy of users of the Site. This Privacy Policy explains what information we may collect about you, how we will use it and the steps that we will take to ensure that such information is  kept secure.

The Site may have links to other websites. Third party websites should have their own privacy policies and we recommend that you read such policies to find out how your personal details are protected. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these third party websites.

YOUR CONSENT

By using the Site, you consent to us collecting and using your details in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

The information gathered pursuant to this Privacy Policy may be used by us and companies in the same group as us (i.e. companies which share the same ultimate parent company) as set out herein.

Please do not submit your personal information to us if you do not wish us to collect it.

If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to be contacted by us, please notify us by email at the following address help@racingpost.com.

1\. Information We Collect

1.1 When you use this Site we may collect details about you, which may consist of your contact details (such as your name or e-mail address) or other anonymised information about you such as your computer's IP address.

1.2 Such details are collected in a number of ways: they can be obtained via the use of cookies (please see paragraph 8 below), or other tracking systems or when you register to purchase a particular product or service from us. We may also collect information you give us over the telephone or in written or other communications.

1.3 We use may use the information we collect from you for the following purposes:

(a)  to fulfil orders you have made for products or services;

(b) to conduct market research and analysis;

(c) to develop the style of the Site;

(d) to verify your identity (for example when you return to the Site);

(e) to personalise your visits to the Site and developing the design and style of the Site to improve the services provided to you;

(f) to inform you about the latest changes to the Site or products, services or promotional offers that you might find interesting;

(g) to deal with, and respond to you about  a comment you have submitted for or on our message boards, blogs and other such user generated content facilities;

(h)  to enable you to share our content with others e.g. using our “Share this article” facilities;

(i) to communicate with you;

(j) to inform you if you have been successful in any Site competitions or promotions;

(k) to compile customer reviews; and

(l) to carry out  statistical, technical and logistical analysis.

1.4 You will not receive unsolicited marketing mail from us or third parties unless you have agreed to this. However, we may email you occasionally with information about changes to the Site and the services available.

1.5  If you choose to unsubscribe from email contact by Racing Post or an associated 3rd party, it may take a few days to remove your details from our list. This may mean you will receive an email before your details have been updated.

1.6 If we contact you via e-mail or SMS we will give you the opportunity to decline to receive future e-mail and SMS messages from us.

2\. Who Do We Share The Information We Collect With?

2.1 We will not sell, trade or rent or make available your personal information to others unless you have given us your permission to do so. If you give us such permission then you may be contacted by our advertisers, partners, affiliates or other third parties with offers relating to their products, offers, services or promotions. If you subsequently decide you no longer wish to be contacted by our advertisers, partners, affiliates or other third parties or no longer want us to pass your information to third parties, please notify us by email at the following address help@racingpost.com

2.2 We compile anonymous records of user trends which we may make use of ourselves, or pass to our associated companies or to unconnected parties.

2.3 We may disclose details about use of our web sites to other businesses e.g. to demonstrate patterns of use to advertisers and other business partners. The information we pass on will not include any personal information by which you may be identified.

2.4 We may forward your personal details to the Police or another regulatory body or government authority if we are asked to do so or wish to do so in order to comply with the law or in relation to the investigation of suspected illegal activities or in relation to any suspected misuse by you of our web site or any or our web site services. Where it is lawful and necessary we may also monitor e-mails you send and receive.

2.5 If you use any of our gaming services, to comply with legislation, we will independently verify your details with a 3rd party agency, who may in turn retain that data for their purposes.

2.6 We may transfer, sell or assign any of the information described in this policy to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change of control, transfer of assets or reorganisation of our business.

3\. Data Security

3.1 We have adopted measures to ensure that users' personal details are not misused, accidentally destroyed, lost or altered. Where information is transferred to a third party, that third party will be required to keep your personal details secure.

3.2 We endeavour to prevent unauthorised disclosures of your personal information by other people, but we are not responsible for any unauthorised disclosures or other breaches of security or for the actions of others if the information was passed to them with your authority or with the authority of anybody other than us or our associated companies.

3.3 Please be aware that if you disclose information on chat areas, forums or other public services it may be possible for other people to use this information. We are not responsible for the disclosure of any information you post in this way.

4\. Transfer of Details Overseas

Given the global nature of the Internet, use of the Internet to collect and process personal details may involve the transmission of data internationally. Therefore, by browsing the Site and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree that we may process your personal details overseas. However, we will always ensure that any third party to whom your personal details are transferred will take appropriate steps to safeguard your personal details.

5\. Updating Your Details

5.1 You can update the personal details we hold on you by updating them on your[ www.racingpost.com](http://www.racingpost.com/) "My Account" or e-mailing us at: help@racingpost.com    

5.2 We may change or update this Privacy Policy for any reason  (for example in order to comply with new legal requirements) so please do check here from time to time to note such changes.

6\. Device Identifiers

6.1 Our Apps require access to the following services on your mobile device: UDID, Mac address, or other applicable device identifiers. We send this information to our servers for the purpose of validating free trials. We may use this information  to seek your feedback on the Site   and to notify you of new products and features and otherwise in accordance with our Privacy Policy [link] but we will not make it available to any third party.

7\. Accessing Your Details

7.1 We will provide you with a summary of personal details that we hold on you upon your written request, subject to an administration charge of £10 per request. To make a request, you should send an email to help@racingpost.com and provide your full postal address and postcode.

7.2 You can also request that the personal details that we hold about you are removed from our system. However, this may mean that we can no longer provide you with the products or services that you wish to receive.

8\. Cookies

8.1 What is a "Cookie"?  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are issued to your computer when you enter a website. Cookies are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive, and they can be used for a wide range of purposes, such as identifying your computer's previous visits to the Site, and to ascertain the most popular features of the Site. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you.

8.2 Types of cookie & the information we collect  
We use two types of cookies on the Site:  
Session Cookies are temporary cookies that are erased when you leave the Site. They allow you to carry information across pages of the Site without having to re-enter this information. Session cookies do not collect information from your computer.  
Persistent Cookies are stored on the hard drive of your computer until they expire and how long will depend on the expiry date of each specific cookie or until you delete them. They enable us to identify your computer when you visit this Site and to collect identifying information about you, such as web surfing behaviour or user preferences.

8.3 What use do we make of the information we collect?  
We use the information we collect from you so that we can tailor content, advertisements and the presentation of the Site to match your preferences. We compile anonymous aggregated statistics using information provided by cookies to develop a clearer picture of which parts of the Site are the most popular to its visitors.

8.4 Third Party Advertising Cookies  
Some third party advertisers also serve cookies via the Site. These are used to serve advertisements on the Site and track whether these advertisements are clicked on by users, to control how often you are shown a particular advertisement, to count the number of anonymous users of the Site and to provide security within transactions. These cookies cannot be used to identify individuals, only for statistical purposes. We have no access to these cookies other than allowing them to be served.

8.5 Web Beacons  
Some pages on the Site may contain electronic images known as web beacons (sometimes known as clear gifs) that allow us to count users who have visited these pages. Web beacons collect only limited information. We may also carry web beacons placed by third party advertisers. These beacons do not carry any personally identifiable information and are only used to track the effectiveness of a particular campaign.  
8.6 Disabling/Enabling Cookies  
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the features of the Site if cookies are disabled.

9\. General

Nothing in this Privacy Policy shall restrict or exclude any liability that we have to any party which cannot be excluded by law. This Privacy Policy shall be governed by English law and the courts of England and Wales and shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any disputes arising in relation to this Privacy Policy and the Site.

10\. Data Protection Registration

Centurycomm Limited, trading as Racing Post and Raceform, is a registered data controller under the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and is registered with the Information Commissioner's Office with Data Protection Registration Number Z2636371.
